findfiles.com 2017-12-14

# FindFiles.com - Privacy Statement

**Information Collection and Use**

FindFiles.com respects the privacy of visitors. When a visitor requests pages from FindFiles.com site, our Web servers automatically recognize the browser's domain name, and IP address. We collect the domain names and IP addresses in order to aggregate information on the pages users access or visit. This information is collected solely for statistical purposes and is not used to identify individuals.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user's website visit. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. 

We use cookies to help you track your recent downloads; to make it easy to check for updates, purchase software, or write reviews. We use an outside ad company to display ads on our site. These ads may contain cookies. Cookies received with banner ads are collected by our ad company, and we do not have access to this information.

**Links to Other Resources**

FindFiles.com web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Website.

The FindFiles Mirror Database can be used automatically when downloading files if you use the [GetRight](http://www.getright.com/)® * download manager.

Using FindFiles.com for automatic mirror searching is off by default when you install GetRight, so you need to turn it on if you wish to use this service.

When searching with this service, GetRight will send at least the file Name (such as _setup123.exe_ ) and the file Size. You may optionally also include the URL so it can be added to the FindFiles.com database and help others searching for the same file. With any Internet connection, your IP address is available to the server you connect to; but no other personally identifying information is sent. The intent of this service is NOT to track individual user's downloads. It is to anonymously build a database of mirrors for downloads so everyone can benefit from faster and more reliable downloads.

If you do not want to use this service, make sure the item is unchecked on the "Mirror Search" configuration page in GetRight ( _it is turned off by default_.) 

Even when enabled, GetRight will not use this service for all downloads. GetRight will only use this service for: 

  1. EXE or Compressed file types--EXE, ZIP, RAR, etc. **No** images, MP3s, web pages, etc. 
  2. Downloads that do **not** use a username/password. 
  3. Files at least 100K in size. 
  4. There are a number of filters on the server side, for specific names or addresses that should be excluded from the FileMirrors system. For example to exclude "cracks", key-generators, or other files. These files are not added to the database, so you'd never get any results if you search for something that fits the server's filters. 
  5. Any files including " **personal** " or " **private** " or " **members** " or " **user** " or " **secret** " or " **/~** " anywhere in the URL are also excluded from the FileMirrors system. 

If you find a file you believe should be removed, please contact us via contact form including the file name and/or URL and why it should be excluded. 

The information in the database may be used for aggregate statistics for things like the Top Downloads on the FindFiles.com website. 

If you have any questions or concerns, please contact us via contact form.

* Several other download managers use the FindFiles.com service. Notably, [Lightning Download](http://www.lightningdownload.com/)™, and the resurected Go!Zilla™.
